Yamid Granda

Senior Front-End Developer

Manizales, Caldas, Colombia (UTC -5) (+57) 3155340563 cyperez51@misena.edu.co https://www.linkedin.com/in/yamid-granda

Front-End Developer with **+6 years** of experience using **Typescript**, **React**, **Vue.js**, **Unit/E2E Testing**, and **CSS**. Interested in creating **world-class** user interfaces. I'm looking for **remote** positions in innovative environments.

EXPERIENCE

Playvox - California - United States — April 2019 - Present

Senior Front-End Software Engineer — November 2021 - Present

- Achieved 1 million in ARR in 2 months (record deadline) by building the software requirements for the new client (<u>Chime</u>).
- Micro leader and mentor to 8 Front-End developers, being dev support to my partners.

Tech Stack: Vue.js 3, Typescript, Sass, Jest, Cypress, AWS, Serverless, Gitlab CI, Storybook, Vite, Scrum

Senior Front-End Developer — November 2020 - November 2021

• Improved by 50% the front-end development speed by implementing micro Front-Ends isolated environments.

Tech Stack: Vue.js 3, Typescript, Sass, Jest, Cypress, AWS, Serverless, Gitlab CI, Storybook, Vite, Scrum

Semi Senior Front-End Developer — December 2019- November 2020

- Improved by 50% the front-end development speed by creating the company Comments Library design system.
- Increased by 85% the code test coverage by implementing unit testing and TDD mandatory process.

Tech Stack: Vue.js 3/2, Typescript, Sass, Jest, AWS, Serverless, Gitlab CI, Storybook, Scrum

Junior Advanced Front-End Developer — April 2019- December 2019

• Increased SaaS sales by prospect from 2 of 10 to 8 of 10 by building in record time each of the specific software required features in the main suite module.

Tech Stack: Vue.js 2, Javascript, Sass, Scrum

Newshore - Barcelona - Spain, Semi Senior Front-End Developer — September 2017- April 2019

- Reduced by 90% development and maintenance costs of each new Airline Booking Solution by implementing a SaaS model with multi Airline support and creating an own Multi Design components library implemented in Airlines like Jambojet, HK Express, Paranair, and others.
- Led and mentored 4 Front-End developers, being dev support to my partners

Tech Stack: Typescript, Angular 2, Vue.js 2, Jest, Sass, Storybook, Scrum

PROJECTS

goalflags.com - https://goalflags.com/ — January 2022

• GoalFlags is a production SaaS free time study side project, created to easily build other SaaS applications using the same components, modules, stack, and experience.

Tech Stack: Vue 3, Typescript, Node.js, Sass (BEM), DynamoDB, AWS, Vite, Vitest (Unit Tests), Playwright (E2E Tests), Jam Stack, Histoire.js, PWA, Serverless Framework, Micro Services, EsBuild, pnpm, mono-repo

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Advanced: Typescript, Javascript, CSS, HTML Z; Basic: Python

Frameworks Tools: Advanced: React, Vue 2/3, Jest, Sass; Intermediate: Angular, Vitest, Playwright, Cypress, Tailwind

Data Base: Intermediate: DynamoDB; Basic: MongoDB, SQL

Tools: AWS, Vite, Storybook, Hitoire.js, Serverless Framework, Gitlab CI

Agile: Scrum, Kanban.

Languages: Intermediate: English; Native: Spanish.

EDUCATION

SENA - Manizales, Caldas. Technologist in Analysis and Development of Information Systems, May 2014 - May 2016